A Guide to the Samuel Powell Byrd Papers, 1823-1859
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Samuel Powell Byrd Papers, 1823-1859.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 39.4
15 items.
Samuel Powell Byrd, 1807-1863.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1939.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm M-1553. Some items transcribed TR/60.
Biographical/Historical Information
Dr. Samuel Powell Byrd was the son of William Byrd, IV and Susan Lewis. Samuel P. Byrd was married to Catherine Corbin who died in 1838. He then married Mary Lewis Brooke. Byrd live at White Hall in Gloucester County, Va.
Scope and Content Information
Letters and accounts of Dr. Samuel Powell Byrd (1807-1863), of Gloucester County, Va., his stepson, William L. Fauntleroy, and his son, Richard C. Byrd, including accounts with Jesse Cole, Nicholas, Vest & Company, B. E. Bucktrout, W. W. Webb & Company, W. W. Vest & Company, and T. B. Taliaferro for medical supplies, household goods, clothing, and furniture; papers regarding S. P. Byrd's notes held by Roscow Cole and Lemuel Bowden; and letters to S. P. Byrd from William Fauntleroy and J. A. Deneufville. Also, two letters from Thomas Marshall to his son, John Marshall (1811-1854), who married Richard C. Byrd's daughter.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Byrd family.
Persons:
Bowden, Lemuel Jackson, 1815-1864.; Bucktrout, Benjamin E., d. 1839.; Byrd, Richard C., b. 1837.; Byrd, Samuel Powell, 1807-1863.; Cole, Jesse, d. 1845.; Cole, Roscow.; Deneufville, John Augustine, 1763-1838.; Fauntleroy, William L., b. 1829.; Marshall, John, 1811-1854.; Marshall, Thomas, fl. 1823-1824.; Taliaferro, T. B.
Subjects:
Merchants--Virginia--Williamsburg.; Physicians--Virginia--Gloucester County-- Correspondence.; Dry-goods--Virginia.
Corporate Names:
Nicholas Vest and Company.; W. W. Vest and Company.
Geographical Names:
Gloucester County (Va.); Williamsburg (Va.)
Contents List
- Receipted account. Dr. S. P. Byrd to Nicholas Vest & Co., 22 March 1831.
- Receipted account. Dr. S. P. Byrd and Webb & Co., 21 May 1832.
- Thomas Marshall to [John Marshall], 21 December 1823.
- Thomas Marshall to [John Marshall], 7 February 1824.
- Dr. Samuel Powell Byrd to Jesse Cole. Account, 25 May 1828.
- Nicholas Vest & Co., account, 10 June 1830.
- Receipted account of Dr. S. Powell Byrd to B. E. Bucktrout, 1 January 1831.
- Dr. S. P. Byrd, receipt to Roscow Cole, 21 May 1832.
- Dr. S. P. Byrd, receipt to Roscow Cole, 22 May 1832.
- Dr. S. P. Byrd for Mrs. George McCandlish in account, with W. W. Webb & Co. signed by William H. Pierce, 19 April 1833.
- J. A. Deneufville to Dr. S. P. Byrd, 28 October 1834.
- Lem H. Bowden to Dr. S. P. Byrd. Typescript, 1 January 1850.
- Receipted account. T. B. Taliaferro to Richard C. Byrd, 4 April 1859.
- Wm. L. Fauntleroy to Dr. S. P. Byrd, Whitehall, London. Written on back of printed circular for Concord Academy. Post 1847. Torn, n.d.